all right Apple number three swears in
the product sap is coming up so I care a
lot about voting with my dollar for
health for the environment for social
justice and so I try not to buy things
with palm oil and I try to buy things
that are organic and that don't have
ingredients that I don't know what they
are that's made a lot harder when I
don't know what the ingredients are and
things sound scary that aren't and
things that are scary are now labeled
benevolent whatever they're labeled more
benign and ice and and so having a way
to look beyond the branding and there's
similar these some of these things that
I will be talking about exist in the
world but they're not owned by everyone
and so therefore they aren't necessarily
open and transparent or they could be be
made much better by the crowd so an app
does exist I have it that I can scan the
UPC of an item and it will tell me the
general health ethical and social score
it has and we'll break that down a
little bit but I can't if they don't
have it I can't add it I can't see and I
think it's very easy to say okay well
this ingredient gets a certain score and
people can just add the ingredient you
can take a picture of the item take a
picture the ingredient list and the
technology can read what the ingredients
are or in version 1.0 you actually type
in with the ingredient is as well as the
country you bought it in because I know
the same product in different countries
is going to have different ingredients
and so figuring out without information
I mean there's lots of things that you
can do this kind of hard because it's
talking about brain stuff but I'm trying
to talk about it from my heart and so
why why a product or than how I'd like
to talk about how
it helps people who have allergies
figure out what they can and can't eat
more easily it helps us be able to vote
with our dollar very efficiently because
anyone can add any product it helps mom
and pop organizations and local be able
to add and say hey you don't like the
toothpaste it causes cancer how about
you buy my stuff here you know it's five
bucks a tube and you can bulk bulk make
it I make it you know whatever every
other month get in on the next order you
can have oh hi I mean I want that
knowledge I don't want to have to look
up every ingredient every time isn't a
carcinogen is it an endocrine disruptor
is it like I want to know I want to be
able to filter it for me also maybe I'm
not that like if I am allowed to the
peanuts be able to say nothing with
peanuts if I'm a vegan nothing that was
ever tested on animals and I think if
you're not a vegan that's probably a
good call but then I can say oh this
corporation just supported a candidate
that I don't like I would like to stop
buying all their stuff what does that
actually mean because it's like this one
company owns all these other subsidiary
companies and vice versa and it's very
confusing and I can see that more
clearly so once we're able to see beyond
the branding the power goes back to the
consumer and to make that easy for
people so you simply take a picture with
you PC or you eventually hopefully just
take a picture of the product itself and
eventually that goes on to being able to
save that information so here's my
grocery list here's my and as we're able
to connect with our neighbors and people
in our area you can say hey you and this
other purse
the cereal you all like together or why
don't you get someone to create bars
that don't have peanuts for you because
these ten people in the city all have
kids with severe peanut allergies and
you use whatever you can use the math
and the data to better serve us as
consumers I hate the word consumers but
we all are who do consume things there
things we need to consume and things we
don't need to consume but food is one of
those things that we do need to get soon
and with our lives it's stuff that is
packaged it's definitely you know loved
and this is going to be on my five
minute limit per Apple so yeah Apple
number three is the product app so being
able to easily see the ingredients and
the ethics behind the products that we
buy